{
  "LANGHINDI": 18,
  "qu1": {
    "ENGLISH": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "<p>Consider the following statements:<br />\r\n<em>S</em><sub>1</sub> : In write back protocol, cache location and main memory location are updated simultaneously.<br />\r\n<em>S</em><sub>2</sub> : Modified or dirty bits are used by write through protocol.<br />\r\nWhich of the following is false?</p>",
      "OPT1": "Only S<sub>1</sub>",
      "OPT2": "Only S<sub>2</sub>",
      "OPT3": "Both <em>S</em><sub>1</sub> and <em>S</em><sub>2</sub>",
      "OPT4": "Neither <em>S</em><sub>1</sub> nor <em>S</em><sub>2</sub>",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "9m/iwvJKC6coEJr5HJJczQ==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME"
    },
    "HINDI": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "9m/iwvJKC6coEJr5HJJczQ==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME",
      "OPT1": "\u00a0",
      "OPT2": "\u00a0",
      "OPT3": "\u00a0",
      "OPT4": "\u00a0"
    },
    "SUBJECT_ID": "13297537",
    "TOPIC_ID": "18434538",
    "QUESTION_TYPE": "7",
    "LABEL_1": "",
    "LABEL_2": "",
    "ANSWER_TYPE": "",
    "fldUnit": "",
    "IS_IMAGE_TYPE": "0",
    "IS_COMPILER": "0",
    "IS_RECORDER": "0",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE": "",
    "fldTextAreaEnable": "0",
    "SUBJECT_NAME": "Technical",
    "TOPIC_NAME": "COMPUTER SCIENCE & IT",
    "DIFFCULTY_NAME": "",
    "ESSAY_SORT": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL": "",
    "FREE_SPACE": 0,
    "ESSAY_TIME": "0",
    "MINIMUM_QUE_TIME": "0",
    "isAnswerFileUpload": "0",
    "RIGHT_MARKS": "1.00",
    "WRONG_MARKS": "0.33",
    "MAX_OPT_LIMIT": "0",
    "TIME": "0",
    "ESSAY_SORT_H": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS_H": "",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE_H": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL_H": ""
  },
  "qu2": {
    "ENGLISH": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "<p>Suppose that in 1200 memory references, there are 240 misses in the first-level cache and 60 misses in the second-level cache.<br />\r\nAssume that miss penalty from L<sub>2</sub> cache to main memory is 120 cycles, and the hit time of the L<sub>2 </sub>cache is 30 cycles.<br />\r\nIf there are 3 memory references per instruction, the average stall per instruction is ________ cycles.</p>",
      "OPT1": "36",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "dfIM/eFb2I8IwPydtwZHJQ==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME"
    },
    "HINDI": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "dfIM/eFb2I8IwPydtwZHJQ==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME",
      "OPT1": "\u00a0"
    },
    "SUBJECT_ID": "13297537",
    "TOPIC_ID": "18434538",
    "QUESTION_TYPE": "2",
    "LABEL_1": "",
    "LABEL_2": "",
    "ANSWER_TYPE": "Alphanumeric",
    "fldUnit": "",
    "IS_IMAGE_TYPE": "0",
    "IS_COMPILER": "0",
    "IS_RECORDER": "0",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE": "",
    "fldTextAreaEnable": "0",
    "SUBJECT_NAME": "Technical",
    "TOPIC_NAME": "COMPUTER SCIENCE & IT",
    "DIFFCULTY_NAME": "",
    "ESSAY_SORT": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL": "",
    "FREE_SPACE": 0,
    "ESSAY_TIME": "0",
    "MINIMUM_QUE_TIME": "0",
    "isAnswerFileUpload": "0",
    "RIGHT_MARKS": "1.00",
    "WRONG_MARKS": "0.00",
    "MAX_OPT_LIMIT": "0",
    "TIME": "0",
    "ESSAY_SORT_H": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS_H": "",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE_H": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL_H": ""
  },
  "qu3": {
    "ENGLISH": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "<p>Consider a two-way set associative cache with total of 8 cache blocks and the following sequence of memory block requests arrived:<br />\r\n20, 17, 21, 32, 20, 16, 27, 22, 7, 16, 32<br />\r\nIf LRU replacement policy is used then the hit ratio will be ________. (Upto 2 decimal places)</p>",
      "OPT1": "0.18",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "sYnmjtIl4KhKJgRApFFLqw==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME"
    },
    "HINDI": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "sYnmjtIl4KhKJgRApFFLqw==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME",
      "OPT1": "\u00a0"
    },
    "SUBJECT_ID": "13297537",
    "TOPIC_ID": "18434538",
    "QUESTION_TYPE": "2",
    "LABEL_1": "",
    "LABEL_2": "",
    "ANSWER_TYPE": "Alphanumeric",
    "fldUnit": "",
    "IS_IMAGE_TYPE": "0",
    "IS_COMPILER": "0",
    "IS_RECORDER": "0",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE": "",
    "fldTextAreaEnable": "0",
    "SUBJECT_NAME": "Technical",
    "TOPIC_NAME": "COMPUTER SCIENCE & IT",
    "DIFFCULTY_NAME": "",
    "ESSAY_SORT": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL": "",
    "FREE_SPACE": 0,
    "ESSAY_TIME": "0",
    "MINIMUM_QUE_TIME": "0",
    "isAnswerFileUpload": "0",
    "RIGHT_MARKS": "2.00",
    "WRONG_MARKS": "0.00",
    "MAX_OPT_LIMIT": "0",
    "TIME": "0",
    "ESSAY_SORT_H": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS_H": "",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE_H": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL_H": ""
  },
  "qu4": {
    "ENGLISH": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "<p>Consider the following statements:<br />\r\n<em>S</em><sub>1</sub> : Direct mapped caches do not need a cache block replacement policy, where as fully associative cache need.<br />\r\n<em>S</em><sub>2</sub> : Direct mapped cache, may produce more misses if programs refers to memory words that occupy a same tag value.<br />\r\nWhich of the following options is correct?</p>",
      "OPT1": "Only <em>S</em><sub>1</sub> is true",
      "OPT2": "Only <em>S</em><sub>2</sub> is true",
      "OPT3": "Both <em>S</em><sub>1</sub> and <em>S</em><sub>2</sub> are true",
      "OPT4": "Neither of <em>S</em><sub>1</sub> nor <em>S</em><sub>2</sub> is true",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "Dsdj/LJX8pBs6q+b96fwiQ==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME"
    },
    "HINDI": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "Dsdj/LJX8pBs6q+b96fwiQ==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME",
      "OPT1": "\u00a0",
      "OPT2": "\u00a0",
      "OPT3": "\u00a0",
      "OPT4": "\u00a0"
    },
    "SUBJECT_ID": "13297537",
    "TOPIC_ID": "18434538",
    "QUESTION_TYPE": "7",
    "LABEL_1": "",
    "LABEL_2": "",
    "ANSWER_TYPE": "",
    "fldUnit": "",
    "IS_IMAGE_TYPE": "0",
    "IS_COMPILER": "0",
    "IS_RECORDER": "0",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE": "",
    "fldTextAreaEnable": "0",
    "SUBJECT_NAME": "Technical",
    "TOPIC_NAME": "COMPUTER SCIENCE & IT",
    "DIFFCULTY_NAME": "",
    "ESSAY_SORT": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL": "",
    "FREE_SPACE": 0,
    "ESSAY_TIME": "0",
    "MINIMUM_QUE_TIME": "0",
    "isAnswerFileUpload": "0",
    "RIGHT_MARKS": "1.00",
    "WRONG_MARKS": "0.33",
    "MAX_OPT_LIMIT": "0",
    "TIME": "0",
    "ESSAY_SORT_H": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS_H": "",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE_H": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL_H": ""
  },
  "qu5": {
    "ENGLISH": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "<p>Consider m-way set associative cache with 32-bit addresses and having block size 128 Bytes. If cache memory has 1024 blocks and TAG bits are 17, then what is the number of sets and associativity of cache?</p>",
      "OPT1": "128 sets, 8-way set associativity",
      "OPT2": "256 sets, 4-way set associativity",
      "OPT3": "256 sets, 8-way set associativity",
      "OPT4": "Cannot be determined",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "fhPK/WKkcuYMengj9uY6cg==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME"
    },
    "HINDI": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "fhPK/WKkcuYMengj9uY6cg==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME",
      "OPT1": "\u00a0",
      "OPT2": "\u00a0",
      "OPT3": "\u00a0",
      "OPT4": "\u00a0"
    },
    "SUBJECT_ID": "13297537",
    "TOPIC_ID": "18434538",
    "QUESTION_TYPE": "7",
    "LABEL_1": "",
    "LABEL_2": "",
    "ANSWER_TYPE": "",
    "fldUnit": "",
    "IS_IMAGE_TYPE": "0",
    "IS_COMPILER": "0",
    "IS_RECORDER": "0",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE": "",
    "fldTextAreaEnable": "0",
    "SUBJECT_NAME": "Technical",
    "TOPIC_NAME": "COMPUTER SCIENCE & IT",
    "DIFFCULTY_NAME": "",
    "ESSAY_SORT": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL": "",
    "FREE_SPACE": 0,
    "ESSAY_TIME": "0",
    "MINIMUM_QUE_TIME": "0",
    "isAnswerFileUpload": "0",
    "RIGHT_MARKS": "2.00",
    "WRONG_MARKS": "0.66",
    "MAX_OPT_LIMIT": "0",
    "TIME": "0",
    "ESSAY_SORT_H": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS_H": "",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE_H": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL_H": ""
  },
  "qu6": {
    "ENGLISH": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "<p>Consider a disk that rotates at 60000 rotations per minute and has a transfer rate of 80 MBps. If the average seek time of the disk is twice the average rotational delay and the controller\u2019s transfer time is 8 times the disk transfer time, the average time to read or write a 128 byte sector of the disk is ________ msec. (Upto 4 decimal places)</p>",
      "OPT1": "1.5128",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "g2rar4e/IvW6JqATwEqceg==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME"
    },
    "HINDI": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "g2rar4e/IvW6JqATwEqceg==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME",
      "OPT1": "\u00a0"
    },
    "SUBJECT_ID": "13297537",
    "TOPIC_ID": "18434538",
    "QUESTION_TYPE": "2",
    "LABEL_1": "",
    "LABEL_2": "",
    "ANSWER_TYPE": "Alphanumeric",
    "fldUnit": "",
    "IS_IMAGE_TYPE": "0",
    "IS_COMPILER": "0",
    "IS_RECORDER": "0",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE": "",
    "fldTextAreaEnable": "0",
    "SUBJECT_NAME": "Technical",
    "TOPIC_NAME": "COMPUTER SCIENCE & IT",
    "DIFFCULTY_NAME": "",
    "ESSAY_SORT": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL": "",
    "FREE_SPACE": 0,
    "ESSAY_TIME": "0",
    "MINIMUM_QUE_TIME": "0",
    "isAnswerFileUpload": "0",
    "RIGHT_MARKS": "2.00",
    "WRONG_MARKS": "0.00",
    "MAX_OPT_LIMIT": "0",
    "TIME": "0",
    "ESSAY_SORT_H": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS_H": "",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE_H": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL_H": ""
  },
  "qu7": {
    "ENGLISH": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "<p>Consider cache memory with an access time of 50 ns having hit ratio of 70%. Miss penalty of a cache is 300 ns. Average memory access time is ________ (ns)?</p>",
      "OPT1": "140 ns",
      "OPT2": "125 ns",
      "OPT3": "110 ns",
      "OPT4": "135 ns",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "fhPK/WKkcuYMengj9uY6cg==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME"
    },
    "HINDI": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "fhPK/WKkcuYMengj9uY6cg==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME",
      "OPT1": "\u00a0",
      "OPT2": "\u00a0",
      "OPT3": "\u00a0",
      "OPT4": "\u00a0"
    },
    "SUBJECT_ID": "13297537",
    "TOPIC_ID": "18434538",
    "QUESTION_TYPE": "7",
    "LABEL_1": "",
    "LABEL_2": "",
    "ANSWER_TYPE": "",
    "fldUnit": "",
    "IS_IMAGE_TYPE": "0",
    "IS_COMPILER": "0",
    "IS_RECORDER": "0",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE": "",
    "fldTextAreaEnable": "0",
    "SUBJECT_NAME": "Technical",
    "TOPIC_NAME": "COMPUTER SCIENCE & IT",
    "DIFFCULTY_NAME": "",
    "ESSAY_SORT": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL": "",
    "FREE_SPACE": 0,
    "ESSAY_TIME": "0",
    "MINIMUM_QUE_TIME": "0",
    "isAnswerFileUpload": "0",
    "RIGHT_MARKS": "1.00",
    "WRONG_MARKS": "0.33",
    "MAX_OPT_LIMIT": "0",
    "TIME": "0",
    "ESSAY_SORT_H": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS_H": "",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE_H": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL_H": ""
  },
  "qu8": {
    "ENGLISH": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "<p>Consider a hypothetical computer system which has DMA support. The DMA module transfer one 16-bit character in one CPU cycle from a device to memory through cycle stealing mode at regular intervals. Consider a 4 MHz processor. If 0.4% of processor cycles are used for DMA, the data transfer rate of the device is ________ bytes per second.</p>",
      "OPT1": "32000",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "Dw90Sw2qduxYLIY1RGzDfg==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME"
    },
    "HINDI": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "Dw90Sw2qduxYLIY1RGzDfg==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME",
      "OPT1": "\u00a0"
    },
    "SUBJECT_ID": "13297537",
    "TOPIC_ID": "18434538",
    "QUESTION_TYPE": "2",
    "LABEL_1": "",
    "LABEL_2": "",
    "ANSWER_TYPE": "Alphanumeric",
    "fldUnit": "",
    "IS_IMAGE_TYPE": "0",
    "IS_COMPILER": "0",
    "IS_RECORDER": "0",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE": "",
    "fldTextAreaEnable": "0",
    "SUBJECT_NAME": "Technical",
    "TOPIC_NAME": "COMPUTER SCIENCE & IT",
    "DIFFCULTY_NAME": "",
    "ESSAY_SORT": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL": "",
    "FREE_SPACE": 0,
    "ESSAY_TIME": "0",
    "MINIMUM_QUE_TIME": "0",
    "isAnswerFileUpload": "0",
    "RIGHT_MARKS": "1.00",
    "WRONG_MARKS": "0.00",
    "MAX_OPT_LIMIT": "0",
    "TIME": "0",
    "ESSAY_SORT_H": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS_H": "",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE_H": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL_H": ""
  },
  "qu9": {
    "ENGLISH": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "<p>Consider the following statements:<br />\r\nS<sub>1</sub> : If compulsory misses are more common then the designers should consider increasing the cache line size to take better advantage of locality.<br />\r\nS<sub>2</sub> : If capacity misses are most common then the designer should consider increasing the total cache size so it can contain more lines.<br />\r\nS<sub>3</sub> : If conflict misses are most common then the designer should increases the cache\u2019s associatively, in order to provide more flexibility when collision occur.<br />\r\nWhich of the above statements are true, with respect to reducing number of cache misses.</p>",
      "OPT1": "Only <em>S</em><sub>2</sub> is true",
      "OPT2": "Only <em>S</em><sub>3</sub> is true",
      "OPT3": "Both <em>S</em><sub>1</sub> and <em>S</em><sub>2</sub> are true",
      "OPT4": "All the statements are true",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "Wkw/v0ACIC+JhZVbmq0HcA==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME"
    },
    "HINDI": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "Wkw/v0ACIC+JhZVbmq0HcA==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME",
      "OPT1": "\u00a0",
      "OPT2": "\u00a0",
      "OPT3": "\u00a0",
      "OPT4": "\u00a0"
    },
    "SUBJECT_ID": "13297537",
    "TOPIC_ID": "18434538",
    "QUESTION_TYPE": "7",
    "LABEL_1": "",
    "LABEL_2": "",
    "ANSWER_TYPE": "",
    "fldUnit": "",
    "IS_IMAGE_TYPE": "0",
    "IS_COMPILER": "0",
    "IS_RECORDER": "0",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE": "",
    "fldTextAreaEnable": "0",
    "SUBJECT_NAME": "Technical",
    "TOPIC_NAME": "COMPUTER SCIENCE & IT",
    "DIFFCULTY_NAME": "",
    "ESSAY_SORT": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL": "",
    "FREE_SPACE": 0,
    "ESSAY_TIME": "0",
    "MINIMUM_QUE_TIME": "0",
    "isAnswerFileUpload": "0",
    "RIGHT_MARKS": "2.00",
    "WRONG_MARKS": "0.66",
    "MAX_OPT_LIMIT": "0",
    "TIME": "0",
    "ESSAY_SORT_H": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS_H": "",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE_H": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL_H": ""
  },
  "qu10": {
    "ENGLISH": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "<p>A cache memory provides a speed up of 7.27 over main memory. If the cache is 40 times faster than main memory, what percentage of total execution time is spent accessing the cache?</p>",
      "OPT1": "82%",
      "OPT2": "85%",
      "OPT3": "88%",
      "OPT4": "90%",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "9m/iwvJKC6coEJr5HJJczQ==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME"
    },
    "HINDI": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "9m/iwvJKC6coEJr5HJJczQ==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME",
      "OPT1": "\u00a0",
      "OPT2": "\u00a0",
      "OPT3": "\u00a0",
      "OPT4": "\u00a0"
    },
    "SUBJECT_ID": "13297537",
    "TOPIC_ID": "18434538",
    "QUESTION_TYPE": "7",
    "LABEL_1": "",
    "LABEL_2": "",
    "ANSWER_TYPE": "",
    "fldUnit": "",
    "IS_IMAGE_TYPE": "0",
    "IS_COMPILER": "0",
    "IS_RECORDER": "0",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE": "",
    "fldTextAreaEnable": "0",
    "SUBJECT_NAME": "Technical",
    "TOPIC_NAME": "COMPUTER SCIENCE & IT",
    "DIFFCULTY_NAME": "",
    "ESSAY_SORT": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL": "",
    "FREE_SPACE": 0,
    "ESSAY_TIME": "0",
    "MINIMUM_QUE_TIME": "0",
    "isAnswerFileUpload": "0",
    "RIGHT_MARKS": "1.00",
    "WRONG_MARKS": "0.33",
    "MAX_OPT_LIMIT": "0",
    "TIME": "0",
    "ESSAY_SORT_H": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS_H": "",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE_H": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL_H": ""
  },
  "qu11": {
    "ENGLISH": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "<p>Which of the following statements is/are correct?</p>",
      "OPT1": "Polling increases CPU overhead because the processor continuously checks device status, even if no device needs service.",
      "OPT2": "In polling, control is initiated by the peripheral device to notify the CPU when it is ready.",
      "OPT3": "During DMA transfers, the CPU is momentarily halted while the DMA controller takes control of the system bus.",
      "OPT4": "The DMA controller communicates directly with memory without involving the CPU for each data word transfer.",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "fUwGNpwrpUE3GIKhfsyzGA==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME"
    },
    "HINDI": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "fUwGNpwrpUE3GIKhfsyzGA==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME",
      "OPT1": "\u00a0",
      "OPT2": "\u00a0",
      "OPT3": "\u00a0",
      "OPT4": "\u00a0"
    },
    "SUBJECT_ID": "13297537",
    "TOPIC_ID": "18434538",
    "QUESTION_TYPE": "5",
    "LABEL_1": "",
    "LABEL_2": "",
    "ANSWER_TYPE": "",
    "fldUnit": "",
    "IS_IMAGE_TYPE": "0",
    "IS_COMPILER": "0",
    "IS_RECORDER": "0",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE": "",
    "fldTextAreaEnable": "0",
    "SUBJECT_NAME": "Technical",
    "TOPIC_NAME": "COMPUTER SCIENCE & IT",
    "DIFFCULTY_NAME": "",
    "ESSAY_SORT": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL": "",
    "FREE_SPACE": 0,
    "ESSAY_TIME": "0",
    "MINIMUM_QUE_TIME": "0",
    "isAnswerFileUpload": "0",
    "RIGHT_MARKS": "2.00",
    "WRONG_MARKS": "0.00",
    "MAX_OPT_LIMIT": "0",
    "TIME": "0",
    "ESSAY_SORT_H": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS_H": "",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE_H": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL_H": ""
  },
  "qu12": {
    "ENGLISH": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "<p>Consider a 2-way set associative cache with 8 cache blocks. If the memory block requests are accessed 2 time in the following order 0, 4, 8, 4, 0, 4, 8, 4, 3, 15, 19, 15, 3, 15, 19, 15. If LRU replacement policy is used, then the total number of misses are ________.</p>",
      "OPT1": "18",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "uVSfPp6W13ZoEas+aZzCdA==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME"
    },
    "HINDI": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "uVSfPp6W13ZoEas+aZzCdA==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME",
      "OPT1": "\u00a0"
    },
    "SUBJECT_ID": "13297537",
    "TOPIC_ID": "18434538",
    "QUESTION_TYPE": "2",
    "LABEL_1": "",
    "LABEL_2": "",
    "ANSWER_TYPE": "Alphanumeric",
    "fldUnit": "",
    "IS_IMAGE_TYPE": "0",
    "IS_COMPILER": "0",
    "IS_RECORDER": "0",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE": "",
    "fldTextAreaEnable": "0",
    "SUBJECT_NAME": "Technical",
    "TOPIC_NAME": "COMPUTER SCIENCE & IT",
    "DIFFCULTY_NAME": "",
    "ESSAY_SORT": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL": "",
    "FREE_SPACE": 0,
    "ESSAY_TIME": "0",
    "MINIMUM_QUE_TIME": "0",
    "isAnswerFileUpload": "0",
    "RIGHT_MARKS": "1.00",
    "WRONG_MARKS": "0.00",
    "MAX_OPT_LIMIT": "0",
    "TIME": "0",
    "ESSAY_SORT_H": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS_H": "",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE_H": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL_H": ""
  },
  "qu13": {
    "ENGLISH": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "<p>A 8 way set associative cache of 128 KB is organized with 64 byte blocks. The main memory size is 4 GB. Each line in a set has 1 valid bit, 1 dirty bit and 3 replacement bits along with a tag. How much tag directory space is present in the cache controller. (In K bits)</p>",
      "OPT1": "42",
      "OPT2": "46",
      "OPT3": "44",
      "OPT4": "36",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "fhPK/WKkcuYMengj9uY6cg==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME"
    },
    "HINDI": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "fhPK/WKkcuYMengj9uY6cg==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME",
      "OPT1": "\u00a0",
      "OPT2": "\u00a0",
      "OPT3": "\u00a0",
      "OPT4": "\u00a0"
    },
    "SUBJECT_ID": "13297537",
    "TOPIC_ID": "18434538",
    "QUESTION_TYPE": "7",
    "LABEL_1": "",
    "LABEL_2": "",
    "ANSWER_TYPE": "",
    "fldUnit": "",
    "IS_IMAGE_TYPE": "0",
    "IS_COMPILER": "0",
    "IS_RECORDER": "0",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE": "",
    "fldTextAreaEnable": "0",
    "SUBJECT_NAME": "Technical",
    "TOPIC_NAME": "COMPUTER SCIENCE & IT",
    "DIFFCULTY_NAME": "",
    "ESSAY_SORT": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL": "",
    "FREE_SPACE": 0,
    "ESSAY_TIME": "0",
    "MINIMUM_QUE_TIME": "0",
    "isAnswerFileUpload": "0",
    "RIGHT_MARKS": "2.00",
    "WRONG_MARKS": "0.66",
    "MAX_OPT_LIMIT": "0",
    "TIME": "0",
    "ESSAY_SORT_H": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS_H": "",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE_H": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL_H": ""
  },
  "qu14": {
    "ENGLISH": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "<p>Consider cache memory with a hit ratio of 80% having access time of 40 ns. Access time of a main memory is 5 times of a cache memory access time.<br />\r\nWhat is the average memory access time?</p>",
      "OPT1": "72 ns",
      "OPT2": "92 ns",
      "OPT3": "80 ns",
      "OPT4": "68 ns",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "9m/iwvJKC6coEJr5HJJczQ==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME"
    },
    "HINDI": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "9m/iwvJKC6coEJr5HJJczQ==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME",
      "OPT1": "\u00a0",
      "OPT2": "\u00a0",
      "OPT3": "\u00a0",
      "OPT4": "\u00a0"
    },
    "SUBJECT_ID": "13297537",
    "TOPIC_ID": "18434538",
    "QUESTION_TYPE": "7",
    "LABEL_1": "",
    "LABEL_2": "",
    "ANSWER_TYPE": "",
    "fldUnit": "",
    "IS_IMAGE_TYPE": "0",
    "IS_COMPILER": "0",
    "IS_RECORDER": "0",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE": "",
    "fldTextAreaEnable": "0",
    "SUBJECT_NAME": "Technical",
    "TOPIC_NAME": "COMPUTER SCIENCE & IT",
    "DIFFCULTY_NAME": "",
    "ESSAY_SORT": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL": "",
    "FREE_SPACE": 0,
    "ESSAY_TIME": "0",
    "MINIMUM_QUE_TIME": "0",
    "isAnswerFileUpload": "0",
    "RIGHT_MARKS": "1.00",
    "WRONG_MARKS": "0.33",
    "MAX_OPT_LIMIT": "0",
    "TIME": "0",
    "ESSAY_SORT_H": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS_H": "",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE_H": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL_H": ""
  },
  "qu15": {
    "ENGLISH": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "<p>Consider 4 MBPS IO device connected to 64 bits CPU using DMA interface. 64 words data is transferred from the IO to memory using DMA interface main memory machine cycle time is\u00a00.5 micro sec. Percentage of CPU time consumed in he DMA operation is ________.</p>",
      "OPT1": "25",
      "OPT2": "20",
      "OPT3": "4",
      "OPT4": "80",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "fhPK/WKkcuYMengj9uY6cg==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME"
    },
    "HINDI": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "fhPK/WKkcuYMengj9uY6cg==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME",
      "OPT1": "\u00a0",
      "OPT2": "\u00a0",
      "OPT3": "\u00a0",
      "OPT4": "\u00a0"
    },
    "SUBJECT_ID": "13297537",
    "TOPIC_ID": "18434538",
    "QUESTION_TYPE": "7",
    "LABEL_1": "",
    "LABEL_2": "",
    "ANSWER_TYPE": "",
    "fldUnit": "",
    "IS_IMAGE_TYPE": "0",
    "IS_COMPILER": "0",
    "IS_RECORDER": "0",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE": "",
    "fldTextAreaEnable": "0",
    "SUBJECT_NAME": "Technical",
    "TOPIC_NAME": "COMPUTER SCIENCE & IT",
    "DIFFCULTY_NAME": "",
    "ESSAY_SORT": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL": "",
    "FREE_SPACE": 0,
    "ESSAY_TIME": "0",
    "MINIMUM_QUE_TIME": "0",
    "isAnswerFileUpload": "0",
    "RIGHT_MARKS": "1.00",
    "WRONG_MARKS": "0.33",
    "MAX_OPT_LIMIT": "0",
    "TIME": "0",
    "ESSAY_SORT_H": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS_H": "",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE_H": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL_H": ""
  },
  "qu16": {
    "ENGLISH": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "<p>Which of the following statement are false?</p>",
      "OPT1": "DMA controller is initialized by the I/O device for number of bytes to be transferred.",
      "OPT2": "The DMA controller sends DMA-ACK signal to I/O device after getting DMA-REQ signal from I/O device.",
      "OPT3": "The DMA transfer begins after CPU relinquishes the bus control.",
      "OPT4": "CPU provides information about number of bytes to be transferred and memory address to DMA controller.",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "+bmGz5JcYnoPEbvGO68hAA==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME"
    },
    "HINDI": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "+bmGz5JcYnoPEbvGO68hAA==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME",
      "OPT1": "\u00a0",
      "OPT2": "\u00a0",
      "OPT3": "\u00a0",
      "OPT4": "\u00a0"
    },
    "SUBJECT_ID": "13297537",
    "TOPIC_ID": "18434538",
    "QUESTION_TYPE": "5",
    "LABEL_1": "",
    "LABEL_2": "",
    "ANSWER_TYPE": "",
    "fldUnit": "",
    "IS_IMAGE_TYPE": "0",
    "IS_COMPILER": "0",
    "IS_RECORDER": "0",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE": "",
    "fldTextAreaEnable": "0",
    "SUBJECT_NAME": "Technical",
    "TOPIC_NAME": "COMPUTER SCIENCE & IT",
    "DIFFCULTY_NAME": "",
    "ESSAY_SORT": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL": "",
    "FREE_SPACE": 0,
    "ESSAY_TIME": "0",
    "MINIMUM_QUE_TIME": "0",
    "isAnswerFileUpload": "0",
    "RIGHT_MARKS": "2.00",
    "WRONG_MARKS": "0.00",
    "MAX_OPT_LIMIT": "0",
    "TIME": "0",
    "ESSAY_SORT_H": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS_H": "",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE_H": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL_H": ""
  },
  "qu17": {
    "ENGLISH": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "<p>Consider two cache organizations:<br />\r\n(i) The first one is a 128 KB, 2 way set associative cache with 32 byte block size.<br />\r\n(ii) The second one is a 128 KB direct-mapped cache.<br />\r\nBoth use 32 bits addressing.<br />\r\nA 2 to 1 multiplexer has latency of 0.5 ns and K-bit comparator has a latency of <img align=\"absmiddle\" alt=\"\" src=\"data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAABQAAAApCAYAAAA1bQl+AAACJklEQVRIS+2WMWgTYRTHfyfiVDoIDhc3CxKhg5rQxSVNcXCoSM4paBIjRTFKIKTSQIVAAwkkS4QoHSxNhOrSUOpWaVqHIpZkisNZENRSg5vUTFJOr/bAa3q5XHrtlpuOj3e/+7//e9/7PuGP+nCEj9AD2nZzv4c7NXJON+OfddzAPN+LPsTdpUaZoEOitPuuX9eFGxSlSS03inscstU3xF19e+HKFpXJMLe2rrOQGWNIPGWYjQFwRxXyEIf06T+w+ZGZyCPeXUyRiV5BPNHemY7AmOM9k6HXnJlKER0SMWH9+4sJcI1A+iasQHA2gbdNiq1aTYDTWuwggRevKIQH0dw07QTzlD885/JClJF0HU+iyFzqqql/HVLWinLpF+v5CW7E1GYJzFIp3MbZ197JjkXZa5ttNsoZ7klpVj1Jlufae2q9D/lNo5LGP5JUoQnmpyfwne8/4Gd3OwWFpvySiDdEqeHZ3/gauje+bE8vo61nD3q8RREE4VDy9Afn8So8lLyWj3oK27moja/Hp8nJcVwnuzqkWoPVCVPLM+qOsTqQpWob2FwnFylQ//aW0mbMLvCneugnWRm+w7mnEtLafXtAZaPI2OIF8nGRpeCwTaDylfKDZ/BkCt/ZH5TtARW2K0n8X/wshp3qbWHTJlCRmbnm5e5Sw7A/BrJV5LgLo+6xuPXsKjzQiprieohlOYW3v6uDXk/TlJX0N1A4gpStDzaLHloH/gXZIIyVZowZHQAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==\" /> ns.<br />\r\nWhat is the difference between the hit latencies of the two cache (i.e., associative hit latency direct mapped hit latency) in nano seconds?</p>",
      "OPT1": "0.75",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "YqxwAPu5ea0jkdSqwkNWXw==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME"
    },
    "HINDI": {
      "QUESTION_TEXT": "",
      "CORRECT_ANSWER": "YqxwAPu5ea0jkdSqwkNWXw==",
      "SOLUTION": "",
      "ESSAY_ID": "0",
      "EASSY_DETAILS": " ",
      "ESSAY_NAME": "ESSAY_NAME",
      "OPT1": "\u00a0"
    },
    "SUBJECT_ID": "13297537",
    "TOPIC_ID": "18434538",
    "QUESTION_TYPE": "2",
    "LABEL_1": "",
    "LABEL_2": "",
    "ANSWER_TYPE": "Alphanumeric",
    "fldUnit": "",
    "IS_IMAGE_TYPE": "0",
    "IS_COMPILER": "0",
    "IS_RECORDER": "0",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE": "",
    "fldTextAreaEnable": "0",
    "SUBJECT_NAME": "Technical",
    "TOPIC_NAME": "COMPUTER SCIENCE & IT",
    "DIFFCULTY_NAME": "",
    "ESSAY_SORT": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL": "",
    "FREE_SPACE": 0,
    "ESSAY_TIME": "0",
    "MINIMUM_QUE_TIME": "0",
    "isAnswerFileUpload": "0",
    "RIGHT_MARKS": "2.00",
    "WRONG_MARKS": "0.00",
    "MAX_OPT_LIMIT": "0",
    "TIME": "0",
    "ESSAY_SORT_H": "0",
    "SORTING_OPTIONS_H": "",
    "TEST_CASE_TYPE_H": "",
    "OPTION_LABEL_H": ""
  },
  "TEST_NAME": "Topicwise Test-6 Part Syllabus GATE 2026 CS Computer Organization and Architecture -2",
  "TEST_ID_ENCODED": "NjQzNDAxOQ==",
  "TEST_ID": "NjQzNDAxOQ=="
}